Contact

afwilkerson26@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/awilkerson (LinkedIn) rhinicornedu.com (Personal)

Top Skills

K-12 Education
Educational Technology
Project Management

Certifications

Six Sigma - White Belt

Pathfinders - Coding for Social Good Certificate

Microsoft Office Specialist Certification - Word 2016

Certified Meraki Network Operator (CMNO)

CompTIA A+

Honors-Awards

Staff Member of the Month
CoSN Next Generation Leaders
Program Semi-Finalist 2016
You Make a Difference Award
Staff Member of the Month
CoSN Next Generation Leaders
Program Semi-Finalist 2017

Amanda Wilkerson

Online learning has hit the mainstream. From corporate training to academia, it is important to get it right. I'm here to help!

Franklin

Summary

Learners seek future-ready skills, problem-solving mindsets, and meaningful opportunities for career advancement. This requires a multi-faceted approach to transforming how they "experience learning". Online learning has made its way into the forefront of our training and education landscape. We should embrace it and utilize its flexibility to broaden the reach of education to all potential learners.

I believe that transformation begins with a simple yet deep focus on adaptability - specifically in the realms of leadership, curriculum delivery, and learning spaces. Technology is absolutely relevant but it does not "stand-alone". It is thoughtfully integrated into each of these realms. Seamlessly. We have moved beyond the gadget. The questions have become, "What learning or efficiency are we trying to achieve?" and then "What tech integration helps us get there in a meaningful/adaptable way?".

It's time to create a movement of adaptability! If you agree - I would love to connect!

Experience

RhinicornEDU
Founder & CEO
January 2020 - Present (1 year 5 months)
Indiana, United States

I seek to change the conversation around online learning in the spaces of K14 education and small- to mid-sized businesses. This is the perfect time to provide learners flexibility without sacrificing growth.

I will work with you to identify areas where an online space could enhance your desired learning outcomes. Then, we will work together to design a space that

maximizes both content and time for your learners. If you are transitioning a current program/course - or starting from scratch - I am here to help!

Additional technology service offerings include: Traditional Tier 1-2 technical support, website services, and project consulting.

Central Nine Career Center

5 years 5 months

Computer Science Instructor

August 2018 - Present (2 years 10 months)

Greenwood, Indiana

- * Deliver dual-credit instruction through a partnership with Ivy Tech CC.
- * Curate and deliver the Computer Science Programming curriculum.
- * Utilize TestOut certification preparation, Cisco Academy curriculum, and Code.org CSP curriculum.
- * Prepare students to be successful in their post-secondary path.
- * Instruct, motivate, encourage, and empower students to advance their programming and critical thinking skills.
- * Sponsor of the C9eSports Team, C9 BPA Chapter, and C9CyberTeam Team (a combo club for CyberUp, GoCyberStart, and Girls Who Code.)
- * Teacher Trainer Team facilitate group training and 1:1 sessions related to Canvas, EdTech tools, and hybrid learning structures.
- * C9TA Treasurer
- * Nextech Education Partner
- * CSTA Indiana Chapter Leadership Team

Technology Coordinator

January 2016 - August 2018 (2 years 8 months)

Greenwood, Indiana

- * Research emerging technologies and areas of efficiency to continuously improve the infrastructure, user experience, and classroom implementation of technology.
- * Responsible for district technology plan, technology budget, and E-Rate projects/expenditures.
- * Maintain network hardware and data systems Veeam, vCenter, Cisco LAN/ WLAN, iBoss, etc.
- * Maintain user accounts for G-Suite, Active Directory, and other student- and staff-centered software packages.

- * Coordinate and deliver all aspects of technical support for approximately 60 staff, 1300 students, and 700+ computers, and various other classroom equipment.
- * Maintain data integrity within the student information system Skyward.
- * Lead the Technology Focus Team discussion topics include FutureReady framework, CTE program enhancement opportunities, SpeakUp survey data, tech training requests, website/curriculum accessibility, etc.
- * Develop and facilitate tech-focused professional development opportunities for staff.
- * Manage the duties and responsibilities of the Student Help Desk and technology interns.

Ivy Tech Community College Adjunct Faculty Instructor August 2020 - Present (10 months)

Facilitate assigned courses as scheduled for IvyOnline - School of IT. I support my students' academic success by utilizing IvyLearn to post syllabus, assignments, and other necessary materials to communicate regularly.

Trafalgar Christian Church Community Outreach January 2008 - December 2017 (10 years) Trafalgar, Indiana

Coordinating outreach through community events and public speakers sponsored by the church. These events include, but are not limited to, community banquets, VBS, back-to-school carnivals, etc.

Nineveh-Hensley-Jackson USC 6 years 5 months

Technology Operations Manager
July 2012 - December 2015 (3 years 6 months)
Trafalgar, Indiana

- * Co-Founder and Co-Director of NHJ Empower an eLearning program
- * 1:1 Device Coordinator for grades K-12 (ChromeOS, iOS, Android, OSX)
- * Coordinate and deliver technical support for faculty, staff, and students across the district.
- * Maintain data integrity within the student information system, Infinite Campus.
- * Implement and maintain all student-centered software programs throughout the district.

- * Maintain user accounts for email, network, and various staff-centered software packages.
- * Develop and facilitate professional development opportunities for district faculty and staff.
- * UNITE Board Member SIS VP for Infinite Campus

ICHS Treasurer - Administrative Secretary August 2009 - June 2012 (2 years 11 months)

Trafalgar, Indiana

- * Allocate and distribute extra-curricular funds.
- * Assure compliance with State Board of Accounts rules and regulations.
- * Calculate textbook rental fees and manage their collection.
- * Coordinate the circulation of textbooks to students.
- * Manage the staffing, purchasing, and accounting of the school store.
- * Prepare financial reports for the school board and principal.

Finelight Strategic Marketing Communications Traffic Coordinator

April 2008 - April 2009 (1 year 1 month)

- * Assist with resourcing of designers, copywriters, and interactive staff.
- * Open jobs and track schedules in Clients & Profits.
- * Coordinate the quality control process for various client and new business projects.
- * Route projects through the pre-press department.
- * Manage vendor relations for outsourced services.
- * Generate reports to analyze resource productivity.
- * Assist staff with various software and procedural issues.

Hoosier Veneer

Accountant/Purchaser

July 2007 - February 2008 (8 months)

Trafalgar, Indiana

- * Point-of-contact for Accounts Payable.
- * Managed purchasing for manufacturing materials, general office and janitorial supplies.
- * Handled client billings, A/P, petty cash allocation, and inventory status updates.
- * Documented the manufacturing process by creating SOPs, automating data collection and training staff.
- * Maintained MSDS documentation and identification.
- * Created & maintained in-house communications.

Willow Marketing

Operations Manager

May 2004 - July 2007 (3 years 3 months)

- Supervised accounts payable, accounts receivable, G/L, deposits, and collections.
- Supervised daily administrative functions such as supplies, maintenance, reception, filing, and client literature fulfillment.
- Generated client billing for approval and distribution.
- Assigned, monitored, and reviewed all projects from initiation to completion.
- Copyediting and proofing of ads, print pieces, and websites.
- Managed purchasing and negotiated pricing and contracts with office, print, and service vendors.
- Responsible for arrangements and scheduling of various meetings, events and activities.
- Served as the primary point of contact for Human Resources. Including payroll reporting, benefits, employee relations, documentation and orientation.

Education

Franklin College

Leadership Johnson County Signature Program, 2022 Leadership Cadre · (May 2021 - September 2022)

Eleven Fifty Academy

Web Development Bootcamp · (March 2021 - September 2021)

Ivy Tech Community College

Certificate - Software Development/Java, Information Technology · (2019 - 2019)

Taylor University

Transition to Teaching, CTE Business & IT · (2016)

Harrison College

B.S., Business Management · (2008 - 2010)